data science is not about making
complicated models it's not about making
awesome visualizations it's not about
writing code data science is about using
data to create as much impact as
possible for your company now impact can
be in the form of multiple things it
could be in the form of insights in the
form of data products or in the form of
product recommendations for a company
now to do those things then you need
tools like making complicated models or
data visualizations or writing code but
essentially as a data scientist your job
is to solve real company problems using
data and what kind of tools you use we
don't care now there's a lot of
misconception about data science
especially on YouTube and I think the
reason for this is because there's a
huge misalignment between what's popular
to talk about and what's needed in the
industry so because of that I want to
make things clear I am a data scientist
working for a Gotha company and those
companies really emphasize on using data
to improve their products so this is my
take on what is big science
[Music]
before data science we popularized the
term data mining in an article called
from data mining to knowledge discovery
in databases in 1996 in which it
referred to the overall process of
discovering useful information from data
in 2001 William s Cleveland wanted to
bring data mining to another level he
did that by combining computer science
with data mining basically he made
statistics a lot more technical which he
believed would expand the possibilities
of data mining and produce a powerful
force for innovation now you can take
advantage of compute power for
statistics and he called this combo data
science around this time this is also
when web 2.0 emerged where websites are
no longer just a digital pamphlet but a
medium for a shared experience amongst
millions and millions of users these are
web sites like MySpace in 2003 Facebook
in 2004 and YouTube in 2005 we can now
interact with these web sites meaning we
can contribute post comment like upload
share leaving our footprint in the
digital landscape we call Internet and
help create and shape the ecosystem we
now know and love today and guess what
that's a lot of data so much data it
became too much to handle using
traditional technologies so we call this
Big Data that opened a world of
possibilities in finding insights using
data but it also meant that the simplest
questions require sophisticated data
infrastructure just to support the
handling of the data we needed parallel
computing technology like MapReduce
Hadoop and spark so the rise of big data
in 2010 sparked the rise of data science
to support the needs of the businesses
to draw insights from their massive
unstructured data sets so then the
journal of data science described data
science as almost everything that has
something to do with data collecting
analyzing modeling yet the most
important part is its applications all
sorts of application yes all sorts of
applications like machine learning
so in 2010 with the new abundance of
data it made it possible to train
machines with a data-driven approach
rather than a knowledge driven approach
all the theoretical papers about
recurring neural networks support vector
machines became feasible something that
can change the way we live and how we
experience things in the world deep
learning is no longer an academic
concept in these thesis paper it became
a tangible useful class of machine
learning that would affect our everyday
lives so machine learning and AI
dominated the media overshadowing every
other aspect of data science like export
or analysis experimentation and skills
we traditionally called business
intelligence so now the general public
think of data science as researchers
focused on machine learning and AI but
the industry is hiring data scientists
as analysts so there's a misalignment
there the reason for the misalignment is
that yes most of these data scientists
can probably work on more technical
problems but big companies like Google
Facebook Netflix have so many
low-hanging fruits to improve their
products that they don't require any
advanced machine learning or statistical
knowledge to find these impacts in their
analysis being a good data scientist
isn't about how advanced your models are
it's about how much impact you can have
with your work you're not a data
cruncher you're a problem solver
you're strategists companies will give
you the most ambiguous and hard problems
and we expect you to guide the company
to the right direction ok now I want to
conclude with real-life examples of data
science jobs in Silicon Valley but first
I have to print some charts so let's go
do that
get in here this you don't live here
anymore you can't just come in whenever
you want can't drive to the office
no thanks for driving
[Music]
so this is a very useful chart that
tells you the needs of data science now
it's pretty obvious but sometimes we
kind of forget about it now at the
bottom of the pyramid we have collect
you obviously have to collect some sort
of data to be able to use that data so
collect storing transforming all of
these data engineering effort is pretty
important and it's high it's actually
quite captured pretty well in media
because of big data we talked about how
difficult it is to manage all this data
we talked about parallel computing which
means like Hadoop and spark stuff like
that we know about this now the thing
that's less known is the stuff in
between which is right here everything
that's here and surprisingly this is
actually one of the most important
things for companies because you're
trying to tell the company what to do
with your product so what do I mean by
that
so I'm an analytics that tells you using
the data what kind of insights can tell
me what are happening to my users and
then metrics this is important because
what's going on with my product you know
these metrics will tell you if you're
successful or not and then also you know
a be testing of course experimentation
that allows you to know which product
versions are the best so these things
are actually really important but
they're not so covered in media what's
covered in media is this part a I deep
learning we've heard it on and on about
it you know but when you think about it
for a company for the industry it's
actually not the highest priority or at
least it's not the thing that yields the
most result for the lowest amount of
effort that's why AI deep learning is on
top of the hierarchy of needs and these
things may be testing analytics they're
actually way more important for industry
so that's why we're hiring a lot of data
scientists that does that so what do you
think is scientists actually do well
that depends on the company because of
them as of the size so for a start-up
you kind of lack resources so you can
only kind of have one D s so that one
data scientist he has to do everything
so you might be seeing all
all this being data scientists maybe you
won't be doing a IR deep learning
because that's not a priority right now
but you might be doing all this you have
to set up the whole data infrastructure
you might even have to write some
software code to add logging and then
you have to do the analytics yourself
then you have to build the metrics
yourself and you have to do a B testing
yourself that's why for startups if they
need a data scientist
this whole thing is data science so that
means you have to do everything but
let's look at medium-sized companies now
finally they have a lot more resources
that can separate the data engineers and
the data scientists so usually in
collection this is probably software
engineering and then here you're gonna
have data engineers doing this and then
depending if you're medium-sized company
does a lot of recommendation models or
stuff that requires AI then the S will
do all this right so as a data scientist
you have to be a lot more technical
that's why they only hire people with
PhDs or masters because they want you to
be able to do the more complicated
things so let's talk about large company
now because you're getting a lot bigger
you probably have a lot more money and
then you can spend it more on employees
so you can have a lot of different
employees where counterfeit things that
way the employee does not need to think
about this stuff that they don't want to
do and it could focus on the things that
they're best at for example me and my
untitled large company I would be in
analytics so I could just focus my work
on analytics and metrics and stuff like
that so I don't need to worry about data
engineering or AI deep learning stuff so
here's how it looks for a large company
instrumental logging sensors this is all
handled by software engineers right and
then here it's cleaning and building
data pipelines this is for data
engineers now here between these two
things we have data science analytics
that's what it's called but then once we
go to the AI and deep learning this is
where we have research scientists or we
call it data science core and they are
backed by
and now engineers which are machine
learning engineers yeah anyways so in
summary as you can see data science can
be all of this and it depends what
company you are in and that definition
will vary so please let me know what you
would like to learn more about AI deep
learning or AP testing experimentation
depending on what you want to learn
about leave a comment down below so I
could talk about it or I could find
someone who knows about this and I can
share the insights with you so yeah if
you like this video don't forget to like
and subscribe so yeah hope you have a
wonderful day hope this was helpful but
yeah thanks for watching
[Music]